SHAIK AZEEZ AHMED

FULL STACK LEAD ENGINEER



<u>Email</u>

in LinkedIn



ABOUT ME

Hi, I'm a Full Stack Lead Engineer with 8+ years of experience with a passion to code that stems from my love for computers and technology. Driven by an insatiable crave for creative satisfaction. Currently working as a hands-on team lead with means to operate in a multicultural team of 8 engineers, Promoter of Agile and a follower of Uncle Bob. To unwind and relax I like to travel, spend time on my guitar or simply hanging out with friends and family.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead

Infrrd Private Limited | 2021 - Current

- Responsible for Feature Analysis, product fitment feedback, design for the implementation and research on new interface development for enterprise Al products/solutions
- Manage 3 core product's front-end design, architecture and API spec by interacting with different stakeholders, product team and create high level design document for the team
- Partly working as a individual contributor for complex graphic works required for AI based solutions, code optimisation for performance, performing code reviews and mentoring team members
- Built and maintaining CICD pipeline using Github Actions for automated code quality checks and continuous delivery pipelines
- Consistently delivered on promised timelines with a team of 7 UI and 1 UX engineer

Senior Software Engineer

Infrrd Private Limited | 2018 - 2021

- Lead the research initiative for interface solution that best fits the team's knowledge base and mortgage domain and its related policies
- Contributed to re-architecture effort for backend migration to new domain standards and third party mortgage integration
- Built an white labelling setup, to customise the application as the customer's specification
- Implemented core repetitive features using Ruby's Metaprogramming to fulfil business requirement to have dynamic, customizable UI
- Extensively worked in Front-end automated test suite, migration of test suite to headless testing due to flexbox adoption

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Computer science and engineering
Visvesvaraya technological university
2011 – 2015

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Ruby, Javascript, Python, Typescript

Web Frameworks

Rails, Sinatra, Node.js, Django,

Front-end Frameworks

React.js, Angular, Svelte

Databases

MYSal, Postgres, MongoDb

Cache DBs

Redis, ElasticSearch, Memcache

Test Suites

Rspec, Capybara, Jasmine, Cucumber, Selenium, Protractor, Phantom.js

Deployment Tools

Jenkins, Docker, Heroku, AWS, Ngnix, Vercel

Source Control

Git, Github, Bitbucket

Web technologies

HTML5, SCSS, CSS3, Coffeescript, Jquery, D3.js,

CSS Frameworks

Zurb's Foundation, Buma, Bootstrap, Material Design

Software Engineer

SIgma Infosolutions Private Limited | 2016 - 2018

- Developed Web and APIs for the iOS and Android, integrated push notification services and mailing clients
- Took up the role of knowledge sharer to make sure team stays relevant to new best practices
- Performed Peer reviews for quality checks and best practices and was responsible to ensure the application meets HIPAA(Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act) compliance during the review process
- Closely worked with the technical manager and the team lead to contribute on high level design documentation and software module breakdown for the team
- Setup payment gateways like stripe connect for linking bank accounts, credit cards and enabling scheduled payouts.
- Set up ElasticSearch and custom script fields, to optimise user search and real time query caching
- Developed Responsive User interface as per designs spec

Associate Software Engineer

SIgma Infosolutions Private Limited | 2015 - 2016

- Single handedly migrated the entire project from Rails 3.2 to Rails 5.1 in stages over a period of 3 months
- Refactoring the codebase to introduce parallel processing with clustering and multi-threading, improve code readability
- Delivered Client demos and walkthroughs of the migrated application
- Maintained 6 storage plant and plant specific configurations, development of new features required for expanding the storage plants specs
- Performance optimization for optimal load average of server, Memory leaks due to redis,
 Connection drop in websockets dispatcher and integration with a SCALA backend that was the core of any given energy storage facility